Daniel Milham

<u>LinkedIn</u> Github Repository (C) 201-268-1719 Dmilham462@gmail.com

Innovative IT professional with experience in implementing various systemic upgrades both hardware and software, project managing, PC repair, data migration, and Point of Sale configuration. Ability to design custom configurations with concentration on integration of mixed technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Node.js, JavaScript, jQuery, GIT, Github, Firebase, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Media Queries, APIs, JSON, AJAX, the command line Adobe Photoshop, MS Office, Analyze bandwidth usage, Construct and Handle abstractions, Installation and configuration of hardware and software, SMD soldering, custom cable crafting, Superior interpersonal skills, with a passion to provide long lasting stable custom platforms.

EDUCATION

The Technical Institute of America

Project Management Professional Exam Prep (35 PDUs): October 2015

Nassau Boces

Hemodialysis Technician Certification

March 2013

The Career Center

Network + December 2002

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Robert Half Technologies

2014 - 2015

Technology Support Engineer - Temp

- Make effective use of help desk request records to identify patterns, systemic problems, and enduser training needs to help improve service and support
- Escalate support issues to appropriate tech department colleagues as needed
- Other projects/tasks assigned by department supervisor
- Effectively prioritize service requests and projects to minimize end-user work interruption
- Perform preventative maintenance on computer systems and other equipment

Apex Evolution Media

Freelance Producer

2013-2015

- Design workflow for file handling for all projects hardware and software related.
- Proficient with the following field audio hardware: Sound devices 788T, Sound devices 552, Tascam DR-680.
- Sennheiser and Lectrosonics wireless body pack transmitters and wireless audio receivers, and wireless audio as well as Countryman and Tram Lavaliere microphones.

Daniel Milham

D.M. Computer Consulting

Owner 2002-2010

- Design custom computers and networks for individuals as well as small businesses.
- Data Recovery for South Side Automotive.
- Point of Sale Configuration for Bed Bath and Beyond.
- Network upgrade for RadioShack.
- Install custom audio visual kiosks and home theater systems.
- Design and built custom electronics.

APPLICATIONS BUILT

Faver 2016

Back End Developer

• Built a web app that allows users to search for a specific product and then have access to purchase it online or find a nearby brick and mortar store that has that product.

• Personally, developed a Javascript based feature utilizing the Ebay API

Crystal Collector 2016

Full Stack Developer

- Built a game where you essentially play blackjack with a dragon.
- Personally, developed a JavaScript and jQuery based game using HTMLl and CSS for front end.

Crystal Collector | Demo Crystal Collector | Github

Get Your Giphy in a Jiffy

2016

Full Stack Developer

- Built a web app where a user can search for random images using search terms via the Giphy API.
- Personally developed this web app by using JavaScript and jQuery for the back end and using Html and CSS for the front end.

Get your Giphy in a Jiffy | Demo

Get your Giphy in a Jiffy | Github

ADDITIONAL WORK EXPERIENCE

Longshoreman, New York Shipping Association, 2006 – 2014 Technician, Drug Test Inc., 2005 – 2006 Sales and Technical Support - Skynet Communications, 2001-2002 Sales Lead, Radioshack, 2000-2001